VINAYAK A. TALAPALLI

DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE

CONTACT +91 7201008561 VITALAPALLI@GMAIL.COM

PROFILE

6+ Year of working experience in the field of Search Engine Optimization, Social Media Optimization, Website Analysis, Traffic Tracking and Reporting. Ability to learn new technologies. Proven ability to gather, extract and use data effectively.

Deep knowledge of search marketing uses of O&A. Blog Commenting. Blogs & Link Building. Extensive understanding of how to follow compliance guidelines and avoid black hat techniques that can damage a client's website

EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE

HK RETAIL | FEB 2021 - PRESENT

- Managing and maintaining the website and this includes SEO optimization
- Successfully spearhead campaigns on social media platforms including Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram
- Evaluating important metrics that affect the website traffic and website experience
- Planning, monitoring, and managing the company presence on social media
- Coordinating with the external marketing team

SEO EXECUTIVE

BLOW HORN MEDIA | FEB 2017 - FEB 2021

- Optimize website and App store for a client which effectively drive brand awareness, engagement, and traffic.
- Achieve a strong, visible online presence. Continuously monitor online public relations and ensure the success of client programs.

SOCIAL MEDIA EXECUTIVE

BLOW HORN MEDIA | FEB 2014 - FEB 2017

- Developed a social media strategy to increase the following of the company website
- · Spearheaded a viral campaign for one of the company's new products

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMMERCE

GUJARAT UNIVERCITY | 2009 - 2010

EXPERTISE

- SEO & SMO (Youtube, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram) • Social media strategy
- Facebook Ads
- Keyword Researching
- Local SEO
- Competitive Analysis
- SEO and Google Analytics
- Link Building
- Webmaster or Google Analytics
- Youtube Optimization
- Competitive Analysis

TOOLS

- Google Analytics
- Google Webmaster Tool
- MOZ Tool
- Adobe Illustrator
- Simmilar Web
- Keyword Planner
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe Photoshop

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that above-mentioned information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.